<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ezyczy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ezyczy.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-09-14T14:48:43+00:00</updated><id>https://ezyczy.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">EzyCzy</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The fear of trying</title><link href="https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/the-fear-of-trying/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The fear of trying"/><published>2023-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/the-fear-of-trying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/the-fear-of-trying/"><![CDATA[<p>We, human, always exhibit some sort of fear. It’s normal, it’s a form of self-mechanism to protect ourselves. But from what? In this post, I’ll be writing about this particular topic from my experience and try to bring an introspection of what is the cause of this phenomenon.</p> <h2 id="personal-experience">Personal Experience</h2> <p>As a person with social anxiety, interacting with people is daunting. The fear of being judged is the biggest concern that runs subconciously in my head, this can be explained (atleast some part of it) by a tedtalk <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LnJwH_PZXnM">“How to not take things personally?” by Frederick Imbo</a> - I often take people’s gaze as a way of judgement. Most of the time, this results in me fearing to do normal daily tasks, helping people, giving opinion in a crowd etc because these event will leave a traumatic mark(a memory that stays in my head) and leads to memory pop from time to time (<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4337233/">anyone interested on why this happens</a>). These mental scars leave me exhausted of trying, and I see this similar pattern in other people. The most occuring reason why people (myself included) that I know don’t try to commit on opportunities usually revolve around undermining their abilities, I can’t recount how many times I’ve heard people saying “I don’t know anything”. So what’s so wrong about staying in a comfort zone?</p> <h2 id="innovation-is-the-result-of-persistent-trying">Innovation is the result of persistent trying</h2> <p>I understand that factors such as having other priority(is) and mental or physical disability plays an important role as a deciding reason not to partake in some commitment. But seeing people with talent, intellect and strong ethic doing so, I find myself confused at times, because they would definitely make a positive change. I’m not going to argue further about this because everyone is entitled on deciding their do and don’ts (well to some extent). After reading through 4 chapters of How Innovation Works by Matt Ridley, I understood innovation is the result of trial and error, and for one to be able to commit on successfully producing a beneficial innovation, persistence is a crucial characteristics of many of these inventors. So it begs the question, ideally, if everyone innovates - contributing to trial and error - then everyday we are one step further than we are currently doing right? Where am I coming from this? A proposition that I thought of, maybe if we try to take a step outside of our comfort zone, then the positive feedback that we gain is not self-exclusive but for others surrounding us too. Instead of thinking “this is meaningless to me”, have it appeared “how people will benefit from this”?</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>I’d go longer if I wanted to, but I’d rather stop with the rhetorical. I might continue on in another part in the future after I educated myself sufficiently. The point of the entire point is to consider a different prespective, of course its gonna look bad for now, but impacts it brings to you and other people in the future, I’d say let’s not undervalue it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="exploration"/><category term="reflection"/><category term="human-behaviour"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[taking another lense on the effort of trying outside of your comfort zone]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What kind of smart am I?</title><link href="https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/what-kind-smart-am-i/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What kind of smart am I?"/><published>2023-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/what-kind-smart-am-i</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/what-kind-smart-am-i/"><![CDATA[<p>One of my friend told me that I was a life smart person - someone whom nagivates life with the upmost efficient way -, I had always considered myself as a book smart person, I like to learn from theory and come up with solution using whatever knowledge that I’ve acquired thus far in my life. Before, I could deny that claim, I thought “maybe he has a point”, so today I’m going to attempt to find a conclusive idea on what kind of smart am I.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>Disclaimer: This writing is not the opinion of a cognitive psychology expert nor does he have any comprehensive knowledge of psychology. Rather just an attempt to understand the way he thinks.
</code></pre></div></div> <h2 id="breaking-down-my-thought-process">Breaking down my thought process</h2> <p>The reason why I initially want to deny his claim is because, I’ve always centralized my thoughts according to facts, theory and assumptions which I gain from reading and just experiencing life. Therefore, streetsmart or lifesmart is the last category I would label myself. However, I’ll try to make this claim a true as possible given my context.</p> <p>In order to do this, I need to understand how my thought process works, I’d simply put it in an algorithmic manner (Let say I have an input of new information):</p> <ul> 1) I look the input in memory, If I find it, I stop. <br/> 2) If not, then I'll try to extract the closest memory that can possibly resembles the input. <br/> 3) then, I try to create a reasoning how this old memory relates to the input. <br/> 4) If it is relatively false, I repeat back to step 2. <br/> 5) If it is true, I stop. </ul> <p>The above is how I believe my train of thought operates. Though it may be wrong, let’s move further from here. Next, we need to recognize, what makes a person lifesmart. According to <a href="https://www.oxfordlearnersdictionaries.com/definition/english/street-smart#:~:text=%2F%CB%88stri%CB%90t%20sm%C9%91%CB%90rt%2F,smartTopics%20Personal%20qualitiesc2">this</a><a href="#oxfordonline"><sup>1</sup></a>, street-smart person is defined as a human ​having the knowledge and experience that is needed to deal with the difficulties and dangers of life in a big city, while <a href="https://www.oxfordlearnersdictionaries.com/definition/english/book-smart">book-smart</a> person is a human having a lot of academic knowledge learned from books and studying, but not necessarily knowing much about people and living in the real world. So, which category do I fit the most?</p> <p>People that know me in real life would vouch me as a book-smart person because I usually spend most of my time learning new things online, this varies to education, health, video games, academics… etc. But according the definition, I might aswell be fit as a street-smart person because I navigate myself through personal and external experiences. We’re in a grey spot here. Before deciding which labels I fit into, how about we delve to some theory of different types of intelligent (in an attempt to understand how professional categorises our thinking style).</p> <h2 id="recognizing-a-few-phenotype-of-smartness">Recognizing a few phenotype of smartness</h2> <p>I could’ve chosen a more recent source but for the purpose of this post it might just do it. According to a Harvard psychologist and professor, Howard Gardner, in his book “Frames of Mind” dated on 1983 states there are 8 different type of intelligents. Im too lazy to write down each of them so I’ll be crediting a <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/03/10/harvard-psychologist-types-of-intelligence-where-do-you-score-highest-in.html">CNBC article</a>. <br/></p> <p>In summary on a scale of 1 to 5:</p> <ul> 1) Spatial intelligence: The ability to think abstractly and in multiple dimensions. Scoring a five means you have a large capacity for spatial reasoning and conceptualization.<br/> <br/> 2) Bodily-kinesthetic intelligence: The ability to use your body in a way that demonstrates physical and athletic prowess. <br/><br/> 3) Musical intelligence: Sensitivity to rhythm, pitch, meter, tone, melody and timbre. This may entail the ability to sing and/or play musical instruments <br/><br/> 4) Linguistic intelligence: Sometimes called “language intelligence,” this involves sensitivity to the meaning of words, the order among words, and the sound, rhythms, inflections and meter of words. <br/><br/> 5) Logical-mathematical intelligence: The ability to analyze problems logically, carry out mathematical operations and investigate issues scientifically <br/><br/> 6) Interpersonal intelligence: The ability to interact effectively with others. Sensitivity to others people’s moods, feelings, temperaments and motivations. <br/><br/> 7) Intrapersonal intelligence: Sensitivity to one’s own feelings, goals and anxieties, and the capacity to plan and act in light of one’s own traits. <br/><br/> 8) Naturalistic intelligence: The ability to understand the nuances in nature, including the distinction between plants, animals, and other elements of nature and life <br/><br/> </ul> <p>Therefore, in this theory of intelligence, one’s intellect isn’t black and white. However, a person may posses one or more dominance on these traits. To fit in my argument, the category (street/book-smart) that I fit in must be one of my dominant intelligence area.</p> <h2 id="reaching-a-conclusion">Reaching a conclusion</h2> <p>We’ve gone so far yet reached so little. Thus, it begs the question, What am I? (wait, lets not go there…) okay okay, so am I street or book smart? From all eight smartness, I guess spatial, logical and intrapersonal intelligence are my strengths. <i>Of course, I do have some capacity for other types of intelligence &gt;:( </i>. I’m far from a streetsmart person, despite having plans for future, a lot of logic is going on BTS<a href="#bts"><sup>2</sup></a>, backup plans among backup plans, and a lot of reading to understand different perspectives. It does not come naturally to me that I’m able understand the world on my own without referencing to others. Although, being a booksmart person gives a negative connotation, that way of comprehending us is a bit naive. Everyone is intelligent on their own ways, as long as all of us are contributing member of society, I believe it doesn’t hurt to be a lil bit different :)</p> <ul> [1] https://www.oxfordlearnersdictionaries.com <br/> [2] Back the stage </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="exploration"/><category term="reflection"/><category term="human-behaviour"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[understanding the different kind of smart people out there (and me)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To the new beningging..benin. beningging…</title><link href="https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/to-the-new-beningging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To the new beningging..benin. beningging…"/><published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/to-the-new-beningging</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ezyczy.github.io/blog/2023/to-the-new-beningging/"><![CDATA[<p>As a prestige whore<a href="#prestige-whore"><sup>1</sup> <a>,going to prestigous university is one of my goals during the ib<a href="#ib"><sup>2</sup></a>. Why? I’m not really sure but I’ve come to regret many decisions that came with it.</a></a></p> <p>After getting a sponsorship, my dream of studying overseas came true. But I didn’t want to settle there, I tried my best to get into dream universities. I did many things that I’m proud of, but one aspect that I’ve left out was my academic. I wasn’t really studying throughout my ib, I spent most of my time doing “extracurricular” which ended up contributing nothing to my application because my sponsor decided to restrict countries to go including U.S. (I saw someone with the same sponsorship as me but going to U.S. lol).</p> <p>Finally after 2 semesters, universities application was open, I applied to UC Bekerley, UCLA, University of Manchester, University of Edinburgh, University of Cambridge (im still proud of my 6.2 tmua<a href="#tmua"><sup>3</sup></a>), University College London and University of Warwick. I ended up getting rejected from all except from Warwick. Well, I guess I’m going to Warwick, but no.</p> <p>Warwick requires 39 with 6,6,6 in HL but my dumbass got 37 with 6,6,6 :skull: (of course I was upset, I scored under personal excpectation of 41), and in the effort of reassurancing myself I told myself, “my 6 in math and physics are very close to 7, maybe they will accept me”. Little did I know, on 17th August, it was 3 p.m. when ucas told me my application were unsuccessful. All hope was gone, and there was I (infront of a laptop), a disappointment.</p> <p>Today, on this very date, 25th August 2023, I’ve decided to fully move on and seriously consider other country options. Initially the U.S. to the U.K. and now surveying Australian universities and among many of them the Australian National University (ANU) attracted me the most. Despite many people says that there are not many Malaysians there and UNSW and Melbourne are better choice for Computer Science anyway, I believe that the opportunies that lies within ANU is beneficial for me that many people dismissed.</p> <p>Looking back, ib was an utter chaos (atleast for me), I’d rather take A-levels, then I would have more time to spend on my interests (and score better). I cant turn the time back can I? However, writing my EE allowed me to discover and learn mathematical research formal writings and write it myself! Oh gosh, I can’t describe the duality of tiredness and excitement as I wrote my proofs :smiles:. IB also help me to explore more perspective mainly culture and language (even though, I didn’t score well in literature). Welp, I cant vouch much about the ib hahaha but I’d say that its very ‘niche’, I aint doing it again.</p> <p>So what now? I have another 5 months of staying here and this is where the website comes to place. I had mostly shared my opinion on Whatsapp and Instagram, I acknowledge that these aren’t the proper medium for I to share my thoughts therefore I made this website. We will see how it goes. Within the 5 months period, I may write one to two post(s) every week mainly to sharpen my writing skills.</p> <p>Thanks for reading everyone!</p> <ul> [1] <span id="prestige-whore">prestige whore</span> - <i>This person is an elitist who cares only about how prestigious their jobs and/or college degrees are. They consider people who attend top notch schools that aren't quite "elite" - such as Rice, Northwestern, and Duke - to be pretty dumb. If anyone isn't a doctor, lawyer, investment banker, or prominent politician, then a prestige whore is simply too "elite" to talk to this TTT.</i> <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=prestige%20whore">[Source]</a> <br/> [2] <span id="ib">ib</span> - <i>The International Baccalaureate® (IB) Diploma Programme (DP) is an assessed programme for students aged 16 to 19. It is respected by leading universities across the globe.</i><a href="https://www.ibo.org/programmes/diploma-programme/what-is-the-dp/"> [Source]</a> <br/> [3] <span id="tmua">tmua</span> - <i>The Test of Mathematics for University Admission is designed to give you the opportunity to demonstrate that you have the essential mathematical thinking and reasoning skills needed for a demanding undergraduate Mathematics or Mathematics-related course, such as Computer Science or Economics.</i> <a href="https://www.admissionstesting.org/for-test-takers/test-of-mathematics-for-university-admission/"> [Source]</a> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="life"/><category term="reflection"/><category term="rant"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[final reflection (hopefully) about ib and universities.]]></summary></entry></feed>